# Birendra Kr. Sharma

## (MERN Stack Developer)

+91-9709857928 kumarbeeru.kbs@gmail.com kumarbeeru.github.io <u>linkedin.com/in/birendrakumarshrma</u>

gitlab.com/rajbeeru675

## **Profile Summary**

Bhagalpur, 813105 (BR)

React JS, Node JS, ES6, Laravel, Mongo and MySql. Having experience of 1+ year relevant experience in Node.Js, 2+ years in React JS and 5+ years with Laravel, and all phases of the Project development like Designing, Development, Testing, Deployment, and Documentations. Here is how I describe myself – Innovating, Executing, Collaborating, and Having Fun! I'm here to turn your ideas into reality. I believe my strong points are my Responsibility and Punctuality.

## **Key Skills**

NodeJS(Skillful), React.JS(Skillful), Laravel(Experienced), PHP, ES6, REST API(Experienced, GIT, SQL, MySQL(Skillful), Mongo, Swagger, Apache, Nginx, Digital Ocean, AWS, Shopify,

## **Work Experience**

## **Software Developer**

Company: Marmeto, Url: marmeto.com, Bengaluru, Karnataka

11/2021 – Present

- Shopify Public App using Laravel, Node and React Js
- Woo-commerce Plugin : Php
- Shopify Payment Getway Node, React and MySql

#### **Software Developer**

Company: Web Revolution, Url: webrevolution.in, Ahmadabad, Gujarat 12/2019 – 11/2021

- Modified HTML, CSS, Laravel, and Javascript Code to optimize the page performance for faster loading and browsing.
- Developed APIs of crypto wallet system using Laravel and MySql and integrated swagger for api documentation as a back-end developer.
- Designed and developed the project using React.js(Redux), Laravel, and MySql.
- Designed and developed the admin panel of Shopify custom application using Laravel and MySql.
- Updated the Mobile Application's feature and optimized the React Native(Redux) code to fulfill the client's requirements.
- Designed and developed the Telegram bots using laravel and python.
- Developed the desktop application using python.
- Wrote script for the crypto trading in python and MS-Excel.

#### **Financial Service Consultant**

Company: ICICI Prudential Life Insurance, Url: iciciprulife.com, Bhagalpur, Bihar 06/2019 – 11/2019

• Explaining the benefits of the insurance, saving, and investment and convince them to buy.

## **Full-Stack Developer**

Freelancer (During My College)

11/2016 - .03/2019

- Understand the requirements of the client and fulfilled them.
- Coordinated with the team and managed the complete life cycle of the project development.
- Developed many projects using Laravel, HTML, CSS, BootStrap, JS, Jquery, React Native, Expo, and MySql.

#### **Education**

## BCA (Bachelor in Computer Applications) (Aug 2018 with 71%)

→ T. N. B College Bhagalpur, Bihar

## Language

Hindi, English

## **Project Summary**

- 1. Easy Parcel Shopify Shipping App:
  - Url: https://apps.shopify.com/easyparcel-delivery-made-easy
  - Language and Tools: Laravel, React and Mysql
  - Role: Full Stack Developer
  - Responsibilities: Database Design, Frontend Development and Api Development
- 2. Project Snapbots Wallet (Crypto Wallet)
  - Url: <a href="https://app.snapbots.io/#/pages/login">https://app.snapbots.io/#/pages/login</a>
  - Language and Tools: Laravel, Angular, MySql, Swagger, Sentry
  - Role: Back-end Developer
  - Responsibilities: Designed the database and Developed the Apis.
- 3. Project: Hospital Management
  - Url: <a href="http://159.65.43.37/anorectaldemo/public/">http://159.65.43.37/anorectaldemo/public/</a>
  - Language and Tools: Laravel, HTML5, javascript, Bootstrap
  - Database: MySql
  - Role: Full Stack Developer
  - Responsibilities: Development and management of the Project.
- 4. Project: Online Test App
  - Language and tools: ES6, CSS, React Native, Expo, laravel.
  - Database: MySql
  - Url: http://hardigurdi.com
  - Role and responsibility:
    - Understand the client's requirements.
    - Researched the requirements and distributed the modules among the team.
    - Designed the database and front-end and back-end for the test section.